Hello Chloe, I'm Andy Davis, I'm HR Manager and I'm a Chair of the Panel. My colleagues
will introduce themselves. Hi, I'm Ian Mullinsen, Head of Health and Safety. Hi Chloe, Jenna
Bootman, HR Advisor. Please take a seat Chloe. I've already brought you some water, but
if you need any more as we go through, please just let me know and I can get you some more.
Thank you. No problem. Chloe, the purpose of the interview today is so we can find out
a little bit more about you in order to decide who to appoint. We have prepared some questions
and all the panel members will be asking questions as we go through. There's no trick
questions in this, they're all about you so you should be able to answer them. Clearly
we will be assessing against elements on the person specification and at the end
of the interview I will give you an opportunity to ask us questions. That's great, very
clear. Thank you. No problem. So okay, the first question is from me, so can you explain
to me what first attracted you to this post? Well I've been in the same role now for about
three years and whilst I've been there I feel I've acquired a lot of skills and I'd
like to put these to good use. Okay, you mentioned the skills that you'd acquired
in your previous role. Could you explain to me what skills that you think you'd
be able to transfer into this role? Yes, I've got good organisational skills.
I've also assisted in organising stock orders and I've also helped out when
organising the casual staff rotors. Brilliant, thanks very much. Good communication
skills are an integral part of this role as is completing paperwork and various
bits of constituent interaction. Can you demonstrate your written and
verbal communication skills? Yes, I have a C in GCSE English and also
as part of my NVQ I've had to complete written assignments. In my current role I
have interaction with customers on a daily basis so I understand the need for
good communication and also for treating people the way that I would like to be
treating myself. Absolutely, thank you. And could you give me an example of when
you worked as part of a team and to achieve a particular goal?
Do you want me to repeat the question? My mind's gone blank, sorry. I'm just
struggling to think of an example. It's okay. Not a problem. Think about your
current role. Do you work as part of a team there? Yes, particularly at busy
times we all dig in to get the jobs done that we need to even if
it means doing the tasks that I wouldn't necessarily normally do. That's great.
Thank you. Have you ever had to deal with a difficult customer or a
customer complaint? Yes, there was an occasion where I dealt with a difficult
customer. She put in a complaint because of the amount of time it had taken to
get served. I had apologised for it and I explained the reason why it had
taken so long. After I dealt with the customer I did report it to the
supervisor so that she could look at the staffing levels at peak times.
Okay, thank you. That sounds great. Thank you. I think that's the end of our
questions now. But as promised, do you have any questions for us? Yes, would I be
required to work at weekends? Well, yes. As outlined in the person
specification and the advert, the role requires five days in any seven
for work. So obviously that does include some weekends. What we'd want to
do is absolutely agree those days with the successful candidate. Okay, that's
great. Thank you. No problem at all. Well, thanks for attending the
interview. We've obviously got a few other people to see today so we're
hoping to bring the successful candidate tomorrow. Which would be the best
number to get you on? Is it your work or your mobile number? The mobile
number would be the better one. If I don't answer then I'll be able to
call you back in my bike. Yeah, no problem at all. We understand that
that can be a bit difficult. But thanks so much for coming in. Thank you.
Cheers. Bye. Thank you. Thank you. Nice to meet you. Thank you. Bye.