[Speaker 00] Hi, I'm Rhea. Thank you for coming to interview with us today. Let's just go ahead and get
[Speaker 00] started with a quick introduction. Could you tell me a little bit about yourself?
[Speaker 00] Yeah, absolutely. First of all, thank you so much for having me. It's an honor to be here.
[Speaker 00] So I've been about myself. I'm originally from Morocco, where I lived pretty much my whole
[Speaker 00] life. I then came to Boston and studied industrial engineering at Northeastern University.
[Speaker 00] While I was in college, I did a few different internships. I did technical ones at a local
[Speaker 00] power plant and at Amazon Robotics. And I also did one in consulting at the Boston Consulting Group
[Speaker 00] and was also the president of the consulting club at my university. So really I'm someone who
[Speaker 00] enjoys both the business side of things, but I also do have a passion for technology.
[Speaker 00] So down the line, my goal is to start my own education technology company in my home
[Speaker 00] country, Morocco, so I can make education more affordable through the use of tech. And
[Speaker 00] outside of school and work, I also do magic tricks on college campuses.
[Speaker 00] Oh wow, that sounds like a very impressive background.
[Speaker 00] So why exactly are you interested in interviewing with our consulting firm?
[Speaker 00] Yeah, my reasons for joining your consulting firm are twofold. Number one, I think the
[Speaker 00] exposure to the strategy work is very appealing to me. And then second, the opportunities for
[Speaker 00] externship is also one that I am highly looking at. So on the strategy side, I know that
[Speaker 00] your consulting firm is one of the few that gives you exposure to C-suite executives
[Speaker 00] and to strategy type projects early on in your career, which is something that I won't
[Speaker 00] find at other companies. Then the second reason is the opportunity to do externships.
[Speaker 00] So as I mentioned, I am interested in the education sector down the line and I know that
[Speaker 00] your company offers the opportunity to work for six months at a public sector type company
[Speaker 00] or a non-profit out in Africa focused on education. So I think those are some of
[Speaker 00] the things that highly appeal to me in your company.
[Speaker 00] Okay, awesome, that's good to know. So now we'll dive into a little bit more
[Speaker 00] behavioral questions. So could you tell me about a time where you solved a difficult problem?
[Speaker 00] That's a good question. I think the moment that I can think of is when I was working
[Speaker 00] at the electrical power plant. We were trying to launch a new department and my task was to
[Speaker 00] essentially source a supplier. Typically we work with a supplier of generators from France,
[Speaker 00] but this time around their capacity and also their pricing did not match our budget and
[Speaker 00] what we were looking for. So what I ended up doing is I ended up creating a large list
[Speaker 00] of all the different suppliers that are out there and then I found a supplier in South Korea that
[Speaker 00] I negotiated with and also was able to bring them in and implement all of the new generator
[Speaker 00] technology. So that was able to save us a total cost of 10% from the total project
[Speaker 00] and it was a huge success at the end of it.
[Speaker 00] Awesome, thank you for sharing that. So next, could you tell me about like one or two of
[Speaker 00] your key strengths? So I would say the biggest two would probably be my ability to persuade
[Speaker 00] people and then the second would be leadership. I would say those are the biggest two.
[Speaker 00] Okay, so could you dive a little bit more into that first one? Your ability to persuade people,
[Speaker 00] maybe tell me about a time you were able to convince someone to change their mind?
[Speaker 00] Yeah, so what I can think of is when I was working at Amazon, one of the big projects that
[Speaker 00] we're trying to launch is the first new robotic facility, but it came out a time when COVID
[Speaker 00] had just hit and I was unable to essentially source a lot of the material that we typically
[Speaker 00] get from our Japanese supplier. So the vice president of supply chain at the time,
[Speaker 00] his executive decision was to push the launch and push it out for a few months.
[Speaker 00] Instead, what I decided to do is try to see if there's a way to still keep the launch at the
[Speaker 00] same time and I looked at some of our existing facilities already and try to source some
[Speaker 00] of the unused material from there so that we don't delay the launch. So initially the
[Speaker 00] VP of supply chain wanted to delay the launch, but through the analysis,
[Speaker 00] through explaining to him that we could source it from the other facilities,
[Speaker 00] I was able to convince him to not delay the launch and instead change the strategy to still be able
[Speaker 01] to get the facility right out on time. Okay, great. So now we'll dive into that second
[Speaker 00] strength you had mentioned. Could you tell me about a time that you demonstrated strong
[Speaker 00] leadership skills? Yeah, the one that I can think of is when I was working at the Boston
[Speaker 00] Consulting Group. There I was leading a big real estate occupancy project,
[Speaker 00] where I wanted to essentially showcase what the attendance of each office looked like.
[Speaker 00] What I had to do was then automate the process for a lot of the partners so that they have
[Speaker 00] like a dashboard that they can like manipulate and change and look at the data.
[Speaker 00] So I had to work with a large team of 15 different developers, software engineers
[Speaker 00] and data engineers. So I worked with them to essentially gather the data,
[Speaker 00] clean the data and process it and put it and visualize it through Tableau.
[Speaker 00] So that was a great opportunity where I was essentially working with different teams,
[Speaker 00] putting game plans, putting timelines for them. And as I mentioned at the end of it,
[Speaker 00] it was a very strong project and the partners were very happy with the dashboard.
[Speaker 00] And it was a good like managerial experience for me at the time as well.
[Speaker 00] Awesome, that sounds like a very worthwhile experience. So now that we've talked a little
[Speaker 00] bit about your strengths, maybe you could tell me about a weakness that you face in the workforce.
[Speaker 00] Yeah, I'd say the biggest one is probably my ability to prioritize when there's a lot of
[Speaker 00] conflicting and competing priorities. The big one in that case would be when say there's
[Speaker 00] three or four different projects and all of them are high urgency or high priority.
[Speaker 00] Sometimes as someone who's still very junior in their career, I still don't have that business
[Speaker 00] sense on which one I should tackle first. But I've been trying to improve on it and work on
[Speaker 00] it. So what I do now is I typically just chat with my manager and try to understand
[Speaker 00] where the business focus should be. And sometimes even just directly ask on how I
[Speaker 00] should prioritize some of the work. So I have been improving on that a little bit.
[Speaker 00] And I think with some seniority, I'll hopefully be able to get there and understand what I should
[Speaker 00] start with first. Okay, definitely makes sense. So those are all the questions that I had for you
[Speaker 00] today. Before we end, do you have any questions for me? Yeah, I think I have two big questions.
[Speaker 00] I think the first one is, as you know, there's a lot of big push for like the remote workforce
[Speaker 00] right now. And as a consulting company, there's a lot of work working directly with
[Speaker 00] clients or coming in in person to visit the clients. Do you think that the consulting
[Speaker 00] business model would necessarily change now that we're are in a remote environment? I think
[Speaker 00] that's a big one. And then the second question that I had for you is, what are the kind of the
[Speaker 00] big goals of your consulting company by say 2025? What are the big milestones that you guys are
[Speaker 00] hoping to achieve? And is say international expansion, one of those big milestones that
[Speaker 00] you're looking at? Great. So I think Zia did an amazing job with that interview. There are
[Speaker 00] four main things that I think he did really well. First, he was very poised and confident
[Speaker 00] throughout the entire interview. We were going back and forth and I was asking him a lot of
[Speaker 00] questions, but he came back very prepared for each question. Second, he used the star method
[Speaker 00] very well. I could really understand the situation, task, action and result. And he
[Speaker 00] introduced each story in a way that made me understand what he was saying. Third,
[Speaker 00] he was very concise in each of his stories. And lastly, he ended with some very thoughtful
[Speaker 00] questions that made it seem like he really cared about the company and the position.
[Speaker 00] Overall, Zia did a great job and I would accelerate him to the next round.